Guide to the Harold D. Gunn Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Harold D. Gunn Personal Papers, 1931-1982, Series V
  - Notes on provinces and divisions
    - Notes and files on Bauchi province (Vol. II), 1950 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Notes and files on Bauchi province (Vol. III), undated (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Plateau province II & III, divisional notes on Pankshin, Wamba, Shendam and Kafancha, 1950 April 25 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - References [to files?], undated (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Research notes [on cards], undated (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Teaching materials
    - "Black Music" [music department bulletin], 1968 July 8 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Lecture notes and instructor's manual for a sociology course, undated (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Note cards, undated (Box 26)
  - Note card file, undated (Box 26A)
- Administrative Maps and Sketches, 1913-1948, Series VI
  Files in this series consists of maps and sketches drawn by the British Colonial government of Nigeria. Alphabetically arranged, most of these files illuminate boundaries and territories of different provinces, divisions and districts. The series also includes historical maps that show territories of some of the Kingdoms and Emirates that existed in the region as "independent" political units. Examples of these "pre-British" political units include the Kingdoms of Koton-Karifi and Kuta, and the Emirates of Dikawa, Hadejia and Katsina. Other important maps include a 1913 map showing railroads constructed in the region up to that year, and a 1937 map illustrating "amended provincial boundaries." One would also find a "gazetteer of place names" on a 1:50,000 scale map. There is also one undated "tribal map" which shows the distribution of ethnic groups in the region. Researchers would also find several other "tribal maps" that often bear the names of particular ethnic groups in the title.
  The series also contains four large "Forest Reconnaissance Maps" drawn by government experts in Lagos in 1947-1948. These maps provide substantial information on the landscape, although their coverage is limited to four divisions, namely Jemaa, Gombe, Pankshin and Tangale Waja. In each map, researchers would find references to community forest areas, forest reserve proposals, hills, escarpments, road networks, foot paths and administrative boundaries.
  - Akpa district (1:250,000), undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Amo, Buji and Jeri districts (1:125,000), 1936 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Benue province and sketch maps of Benue-Adamawa boundary, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Birniwa district of Hadejia emirate (1:125,000), undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Bornu, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - District of "Gala Mela" (formerly called Ojoko), undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Ganda and Lala districts, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Gazetteer of place names on the 1/50,000 maps of Nigeria, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Hand drawn sketch of a settlement (name and scales not given), undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Idoma division, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Kankara district (Katsina division), 1947 November (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Katagun division (1;250,0000), undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Limits of the former Kuta Chiefdom, 1936 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - The Madagali area (1:250:000), 1935 July 18 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Map of Kwolla tribal area (1:100, 000), undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Map of Potiskun division [broken and illegible], undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Montel and Yergam area (drawing No. M2272, traced by Asoritola and checked by Edemoku), scale, 1:250,000, 1934 November (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Northern and Southern provinces boundaries, 1936 March 16 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Numan division (Adamawa province), undated (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Odo Owa-IloffaV.A.sand Odo Owa-Erinmope V.A.s boundaries (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Otukpa, Ocheku, Boju, Oturkpo, Adoka and Yangedde districts, sketch maps of, undated (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Shendam division [several sketches, no scale given], undated (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Sketch map of Bunu district (1:250,000), undated (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Sketch maps of Dakka, Gassol and Mutum Biyu districts, Muri Division [scale 1/250,000], undated (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Sketch map illustrating amended Plateau-Zaria provincial boundary (1:30,000), 1937 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Sketch map of Kadara area (1;250,000), undated (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Sketch maps of Karshi, Yeskwa and neighboring districts (scale, 1"/8 miles), undated (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Sketch map of a settlement scheme, undated (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Sketch maps of Ukan, Ukum, Shenev, Ipav, Mbatie, Ugondo, Ngohor, Shangev West, Utange, Utiondo, Mbakar, Tambo West, Masev and Ngenev districts, [1946?] (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Sketch maps and various draft notes on the Plateau area of northern Nigeria, undated (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Various sketches and sketch paper drafts, undated (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Vegetational map of Biu division, Bornu (1:500,000), undated (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Wase district, Shendam division (1:500,000), undated (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Yan Daka, Katsina Emirate (1: 187,000), undated (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Yangur district and part of Song (1:125,000), 1936 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Oversize maps
    - Bula, Dass, Ganjua, Lame, Lere and Sayawa areas (1:500,000), 1930 April 5 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Dikawa Emirate (1:125,000), undated (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Forest reconnaissance maps
      - Gombe division forest reconnaissance map (1:250,000 or 1.04" to 4 miles), 1948 (Box 28, Folder 38)
      - Jemaa division forest reconnaissance map (1:62,500 or 1.014" to 1 mile), 1948 (Box 28, Folder 39)
      - Pankshin division forest reconnaissance map (1:125,000 or 1.014 to 2 miles), 1948 (Box 28, Folder 40)
      - Tangale Waja forest reconnaissance map (1:125,000 or 1.014" to 2 miles), 1948 (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Kamuku area of Kuta division (1:125,000), undated (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - The Kingdom of Koton-Karifi (1:125,000), 1936 April 30 (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Map of Kede district, Bida division (1:250,000), undated (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - Map E. Northern and Southern Nigeria (showing railways constructed up to June 1913), scale, 1/ 2000000, 1913 June (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - Northern Jos division (1:65,500 or 1.014" to 1 mile), 1947 (Box 28, Folder 46)
    - Northern Provinces (Nigeria) tribal map (1;2000,000, undated (Box 28, Folder 47)
    - Plateau province (1:500,000 or 1.014" to 8 miles, undated (Box 28, Folder 48)
    - Sketch map of the territory of Kuta pre-British (1:250,000), 1934 August 30 (Box 28, Folder 49)